Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/aatif-mohammed (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Economics Analytical Skills Data Analytics

Languages

Hindi (Limited Working)
Urdu (Limited Working)
English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Advanced Product Management Corporate Finance & Accounting Managerial Economics Business Analytics

Aatif Mohammed

Senior Product Manager @ Boston Dynamics | Ex- Facebook (Meta) | Hardware & Software Product Management | I Introduce New Products In Emerging Markets!

Washington DC-Baltimore Area

Summary

Senior Product Manager at Boston Dynamics managing several Hardware and Software products under the payload portfolio (Computational Hardware, Light and Sound Systems, Camera Systems, Microphone Arrays, Packaging, Manipulation Tools). Previously a New Product Introduction PM at Facebook (Meta) focused on entertainment products.

#Managed comprehensive Hardware Product Portfolio of [7+] products resulting in brand new market opportunity for industrial robotics

#Launched [60+] products across the Audio, Live Audio, Video, Live Video, and Community space by building out scaled tooling solutions for content reviewers, testing product features, defining key metrics, and managing numerous cross-functional relationships. As a result, [30k+] harmful content had been actioned on the platform

#Several years of engineering & project management experience overseeing complex technical efforts across [3+] industries

Interested in chatting? Send me a DM!

Experience

Boston Dynamics Senior Product Manager March 2022 - Present (2 years 10 months) United States

Facebook

New Product Introduction (NPI) Program Manager January 2021 - March 2022 (1 year 3 months)

United States

Responsibilities within Software Product Management and Program Management...

- > Launched [60+] products across the Audio, Live Audio, Video, Live Video, Instagram, and Community space by building out scaled tooling solutions for content reviewers, testing product features, defining key metrics, and managing numerous cross-functional relationships. As a result, 30k+ harmful content had been actioned on the platform
- > Unlocked [15+] operational metrics for my organization by defining key logging information and redefining internal processes. This reduced data input from 4 locations to 2 locations (a reduction of 50%) and the newly found data is able to be visually represented in Tableau to monitor efficiency, health, and quality of product operations.
- > Centralized [100%] of product roadmap information into internal demand forecast by creating a mathematical model to consider key factors such as # Launches, User Engagement, Stage in Product Cycle, and Company Priority. The model enabled the Global Operations to plan for tooling optimization, staffing & policy changes based on future vision
- > Matured the operational protocol for Social Audio to 100% scale by driving several escalations with cross-functional orgs like Automation Engineering and Operational Readiness, implementing creative risk mitigation for Proactive Classifiers, and restructuring tooling queues to better allocate raters and prioritize the most severe content.

Raytheon Technologies
Engineering Program Manager
June 2017 - December 2020 (3 years 7 months)
Waltham, Massachusetts, United States

Product Test Lead:

- > Directed 88+ Radio-Frequency (RF) test cases to gauge the fidelity of 4
 Rocket Receiver Assemblies. Formulated 7+ scripts to examine product output
 KPIs such as rise-time, noise reduction, and image rejection.
- > Spearheaded 13+ environment validation tests such as Vibration, Temperature, Resistance, Calibration, and Final Sales tests to assess product KPIs under stressing environments for an international customer.

Engineering Project Manager:

> Managed budget over \$450,000 for Quality Engineering and Product Support teams totaling 14 individuals. Evaluated cost, schedule, and other Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) on a weekly and monthly basis to gauge program health.

Product Strategist:

> Supported business capture of programs worth \$2B for an international customer by providing engineering analysis, contract development, financial modeling, supply-chain strategy, data visualization, and marketing material development support across multiple (3+) proposals

Process Improvement Specialist:

> Established an Agile & Scrum strategy to improve project execution and support teams totaling 34+ individuals. Increased project placement efficiency by >50% and enhanced project quality

Virtual Reality Investigation Lead:

> Team lead for a virtual-reality business proposal project aimed toward investigating & capturing intellectual property for Raytheon

New York University
Rapid Prototyping, Engineering Assistant
August 2016 - May 2017 (10 months)
Makerspace Laboratory

- > Oversaw the operation of 3-D printers, 3-D scanners, laser cutters, and milling machines critical for university research.
- > Trained over 100 engineering students on how to use state-of-the-art laboratory equipment for technical projects.
- > Provided Computer Aided Design (CAD) modeling support to aid rapid prototype development

Honeywell Aerospace Hardware Engineering Intern May 2016 - September 2016 (5 months) Torrance, CA

- > Supported the engineering, manufacturing, and design of a Ram Air Turbine utilized for emergency power generation.
- > Chaired a solenoid actuator research effort focused on turbine flap deployment and presented the results at a Product Design Review.
- > Built assembly instructions and detailed weight comparisons of the turbine sub-system for integration into customer aircraft.
- > Implemented a competitive intelligence database to evaluate company portfolio and determine gaps in the product line.
- > Developed Qualification Test Plans (QTP), Validation and Verification (V&V) documents, and Written Evidence Reports (WER's) to stream-line future testing efforts

New York Power Authority Hardware Engineering Intern May 2015 - August 2015 (4 months) Astoria, NY

- > Formulated drawings for the Combustion Turbine Bleed Valve Replacement Project in collaboration with General Electric.
- > Performed thermal inspections of plant's drain lines and tested the accuracy of pressure meters to sustain plant efficiency.
- > Pioneered custom arc-flash warning labels that met the National Fire Protection Agency's safety standards.
- > Interpreted Parts & Instrumentation Diagrams to create a catalog of significant plant assets and tools. Audited major plant repairs and operating procedures for facility management

New York University
Electronics Research Intern
July 2014 - September 2014 (3 months)
Brooklyn, NY

Made a functional Chua's Circuit from parts readily available in electronic stores. Used TL082 integrated circuits, capacitors, resistors, switch, led, and potentiometers to simplify circuit design. Created a simplified guide for online followers. Published work as an author to IEEE.

Education

New York University
Bachelor's Degree, Mechanical Engineering